

Sergey Sova

email: work@sergeysova.com cell phone: +374 55 544011 code: github.com/sergeysova

LANGUAGE

Russian: Native English: B2

SKILLS

TypeScript, React, Effector, Node.JS, Rust, Git, Unix

EDUCATION

FGBOU SPO "GK" // RUSSIA Bachelor's Degree

Technician, Computer Software and Multimedia Applications 2009 - 2013

ABOUT ME

I had made a bunch of packages for the effector ecosystem: patronum, logger, inspector, etc.

I'm consulting people and companies for frontend architecture principles and React optimizations.

Now I am researching AI, using, programming, finetuning.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Deputy Chief Technical Officer // 9 months Haiku // Full-time // Sep 2021 — May 2022

- Setup processes and aligned technology stack in the five web development teams. Conducted one-to-one meetings as a mentor in the team to grow skills and help with personal development.
- Consulted the teams on the edge technologies effector, feature-sliced.design, react, typescript. Made code review for architectural complexities.
- Responsible for the final stage of the tech interview. Created and implemented a plan to grow the team and improve skills.

Head of Web-Development Department // 11 months Mission:Luna // Full-time // Nov 2020 — Sep 2021

- Setup a web development circle of the different team members, hired about 10 people for the team and trained them for internal standards.
- Setup assessment, code review, and retrospective processes.
- Built the API review and approval process of the backend.
- Mentored team members to grow their skills and improve communication within the team. I have grown developer from the junior level into middle+ for 9 months.

Frontend Development Lead // 18 months Redmadrobot // Full-time // Jul 2019 — Nov 2020

- Designed and had implemented a cross code-review. Began to conduct internal meetings between staff.
- Formalized the process of the API review, and suggestions for improvements to speed up internal communications.
- Had written an internal application for Swift/Kotlin app debugging.
- Trained the team for AtomicDesign and feature-sliced.design
- Organized a public frontend meetup in St. Petersburg for 200 attendees.

Senior Backend Developer // 5 months Akropolis LLC // Remote // Oct 2018 — Feb 2019

- Made internal REST-like web-server on Rust for Ethereum blockchain node. Designed API to communicate with React app.
- Participated in the smart-contracts development on Solidity for Polkadot, Parity, and Ethereum.

Senior UI Developer // 13 months Yandex LLC // Full-time // Sep 2017 — Sep 2018

- Made a frontend application for Yandex.Mail via React,
 TypeScript, Node.js, and Redux. Designed API for the backend.
- Optimized Node.Js service to perform many responses per sec.
- Spoke on the meetup about architectural approaches in developing large frontend applications on React.

Also, I have 5 years 5 months of the Web-development XP